Nimila Hiranya Samarasinghe

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PRIMARY CONTACT

+94 75 66 333 95 nimila@applova.co nimilahiran@gmail.com

ADDRESS

25 Daya Road, Wellawatte, Sri Lanka 00600

SOCIAL

https://nhiranz.github.io

PROFILE

Technically astute Software Engineer, with 3+ years of experience in building Software Products and Brands in the industry, as a fully fledged Full Stack Developer.

Has been involved with a globally reputed product and platform since it's inception, and has been a key factor in honing the said platform to the standard where it is at now today.

Experienced in Java, React Native, Android, and Javascript Frameworks. Has a high competency in crafting sound UI solutions for products, ranging from Mobile Apps, Web Uls.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER @ APPLOVA INC.

MARCH 2019 - TO DATE

Has been a part of the core development team of Applova.io since it's inception. Was involved in Mobile, Web, API and Payments related modules and projects.

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER @ HSENID MOBILE SOLUTIONS

JULY 2017 - MARCH 2019

Was involved in different projects, mainly focussing on Applova(Then in incubation stage) in different aspects.

INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER @ HSENID MOBILE SOLUTIONS

JULY 2015 - JUNE 2016

Worked in several projects which were related to Telco and other in-house products. Developed and researched with React Native primarily in creating the initial version of Applova Mobile Order Ahead Apps.

DESIGNER @ THE LOGO PATROL

NOVEMBER 2014 - TO DATE

Initiated and is in standing as the Chief Designer at Brand Consultancy Firm, The Logo Patrol. Has been a part of over 30+ projects ranging from branding to company portfolios.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING(B.ENG) UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER, LONDON **SEPTEMBER 2013 - MAY 2017**

Second Class Upper Honors Holder for Bachelor of Engineering - Software Engineering from University of Westminster, London. Completed the degree at the offshore campus, Informatics Institue of Technology, Colombo.

CERTIFICATE IN MASTER JAVA DEVELOPER **IJSE**

2013

Has completed the Certificate in Master Java Developer (CMJD) course at Institute of Java and Software Engineering (IJSE).

Nimila Hiranya Samarasinghe

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PRIMARY CONTACT

+94 75 66 333 95 nimila@applova.co nimilahiran@gmail.com

ADDRESS

25 Daya Road, Wellawatte, Sri Lanka 00600

SOCIAL

https://nhiranz.github.io

CERTIFICATE IN BUSINESS ACCOUNTING CIMA

2013

Has completed the Certificate in Business Accounting(Level 01) at CIMA (Apex Institute, Galle) in 2013.

STUDY OF UNITED STATES INSTITUTES UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON, USA 2016

Was a Student Journalist/Analyst representing Sri Lanka at Study of United States Institutes conducted by International Understanding Through Students in University of Washington, with the sponsoship of State Department of United States.

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

COMPETENT COMMUNICATOR/COMPETENT LEADERSHIP

TOASTMASTERS INTERNATIONAL 2016

Completed both the manuals in 2016, whilst being the Charter President of IIT Toastmasters Club. Currently pursuing Pathways, whilst being the Vice President, Public Relations at COYLE Toastmasters Club.